Impossible… He took us all out
in one swoop!
バカな！ 俺たちが
たった一撃で…。
盗賊どもが。
It was a blessing
that this gang of thieves
escaped into our territory.
この区域に逃げ込んだのが
運のツキだったな。
(タイコ)俺たちのトップは いまや
組織一の実力を誇る副隊長だ。
Our superior is none other
than the lieutenant,
the most skilled in
the organization,
our pride and joy.
逃げきれるわけがないだろ。
There's no way
you could've gotten away.
Brilliant as usual.
相変わらずのお手並みです。
それで こいつらは？
So? What do we do with them…?
(サスケ)いつもどおりだ。
What we always do.
了解。 おい お前ら！
Understood.
Hey, guys!
見せしめに痛めつけてやれ！
お～っ！
Teach them a lesson and
make an example out of them!
あんなにひどく
痛めつけなくてもね。
Do they have to
beat them up so much?
Lately, their methods
have been extreme!
最近のやり方は目に余るよ。
風紀を守るためとか言ってさ➡
They say it's to maintain
public morals…
あっちこっちで威張りくさって。
But they're just throwing
their weight around.
何か言ったか？
おお怖っ！
Did you say something?
Oh, scary!
下手に関わったら
こっちまでしょっ引かれる。
We'd better watch what we say,
or we're gonna get it too!
フンッ。
(サクラ)サスケ君…。
Sasuke…
LEAF POLICE FORCE
Jiraiya Ninja Scrolls:
The Tale of Naruto the Hero-
The Difference in Power
最初は過激だと思ったが➡
ON STANDBY
I thought it would be
too extreme at first…
But seeing the results,
it all ended up being a good idea.
結果的に いいアイデアだったよな。
あれだけ痛めつければ
罪人は二度と悪さはしない。
If we hurt them enough,
bad guys won't resort
to crime again.
The same goes with the villagers.
それを見た里の者たちも同様。
抑止力になって 一石二鳥だ。
This acts as a preventative
so we're killing two birds
with one stone.
No…We get to let off steam too,
いや 俺らのガス抜きも兼ねて
一石三鳥かもな。
so it's like killing three birds
with one stone!
Honestly, until Mr. Sasuke came,
everyone was getting fed up.
実のところ サスケさんが来るまでは
ずっとクサクサしてた。
Our main issue was at a standstill
いつまでも
例の件は進まないのに➡
while our work kept
increasing steadily.
仕事の量だけ増えるんだからな。
All Captain Fugaku says is
to heed the Hokage and wait.
火影に従えと フガク隊長は
待つことばかりを強いてくる。
待ってるだけで
状況が変わるなら➡
If things were going
to change by waiting,
they would've changed long ago.
うちはの扱いは
とっくに変わっている。
Absolutely…
(タイコ)そのとおり こっちからも
圧力をかけてやらないとな。
We have to apply pressure too.
Lord Fugaku's ways
are too weak.
フガクさんのやり方は甘すぎる。
We're going to
follow you, Lieutenant.
俺たちは 副隊長についていくぞ！
フンッ。
((フガク : 偉そうな口なら
誰にでもきける。
Talk is easy.
(実際に任務について
お前の力を示してみろ))
Now demonstrate your skills
in a real mission.
《この程度のこと 造作もない》
This isn't difficult at all…
(ヒルゼン)最近の警務部隊の活動は
目に余るのう。
The recent activities of
the Leaf Police Force
are unpardonable!
There's no doubt that
crime has gone down,
確かに 以前より犯罪は
少なくなったが➡
里の者たちの不満は
日ごとに高まるばかり。
but the villagers are
growing uneasy by the day.
(ミナト)彼らなりの抗議でも
あるんでしょう。
It must be a form of protest.
いつまでも
事態が動かないことに イラだち➡
They must be annoyed
because their circumstances
remain unchanged…
業を煮やしている。
They're starting to
lose patience.
(イタチ)物事が変わっていくには
時間が必要。
Change takes time.
それは 父も理解しています。
My father understands this.
ですが それを
もどかしく感じる者たちもいる。
However, others feel
frustrated by this.
特に 若い世代の者たちには。
Especially the younger generation.
And the one at
the center of all this is…
その中心にいるのが➡
今や 一族上位の実力を持つ
サスケ君か。
the clan's most gifted member,
Sasuke.
Sasuke, you're back.
((サスケ 戻っていたのか？))
荒っぽくはありますが➡
Perhaps they're being rough,
but they've haven't deviated
from their duties.
彼らは まだ任務の枠を
逸脱してはいない。
父は 見守る方針のようです。
I believe my father would still
like to keep observing them.
確かに 下手な処分は➡
And if we make the wrong move,
we'll only invite more resistance.
かえって 反発を招きかねないか。
(シカマル)あ～あ まいるよな。
What a drag…
Everyone's so uptight in
the village because of them…
あいつらのせいで
里の空気が ギスギスしててよ。
It's so annoying.
(チョウジ)いい迷惑だよ
このへんだって➡
Until recently, this used to be
such a lively place
ちょっと前まで
屋台なんかで賑わってたのにさ。
filled with food stands!
何でもかんでも取り締まるから
すっかり寂れちゃったし。
Since they're so strict about
regulating everything…
it's so deserted now.
(いの)ほんとよね
サスケ君 何考えてんだろ？
I know. I want to know
what Sasuke's thinking…
とはいっても 今は
近づける雰囲気じゃないのよね。
But he's so unapproachable
these days.
Do you think it will ever
go back to how it was?
もう 前みたいには
戻れないのかな？
This is strange…
(ナルト)おっかしいな。
(２人)ん？
このへん もっと
屋台とかなかったっけ？
Weren't there lots of
food stands here before?
この声って。
もしかして ナルト!?
That voice!
Is it…Naruto?!
えっ？ サクラちゃん？
Sakura!
みんな！
お前 いつ戻ってきたんだよ。
You guys!
When did you get back?
ついさっき！
Just now.
Pervy Sage had to make a stop,
so I just came home first.
エロ仙人は 寄るところがある
って言うからさ➡
ひと足先に
帰ってきたんだってばよ。
へ～ あんた ちょっと
立派になったんじゃない？
You kinda look a little
more distinguished!
Really?
そうか？
みんなは全然変わんねえな。
You guys haven't changed at all!
What're you saying?
We've changed a lot.
何言ってんだ
すげえ変わったぞ ほら。
Look!
あ！ それって！
That's—!
While you were gone,
we all became chunin.
あんたが旅してる間に
みんな中忍になったのよ。
Not only that, Neji,
who was a class ahead of us,
ちなみに一つ上のネジさんは
上忍になってるし。
is now a jonin.
Which means…
ってことは 同期のなかで
俺だけが下忍なのかよ！
I'm the only one from
our class who's still a genin?!
いや そういえばサスケもそうか。
Actually…Sasuke is one too.
Since he was at the Feudal Lord's
office all this time.
ずっと大名府にいたんだもんね。
なんだよ サスケがどうかしたのか？
What's going on with Sasuke?
Yeah, well…
あぁ まあな。 お前がいない間に➡
Since you've been away,
things have gotten
a little complicated.
ちょっと面倒なことになっててよ。
Hey you!
(タイコ)おい 貴様！
誰の許可を得て店を出してる！
Who gave you permission
to open up shop?!
すみません でも今までは…。
I'm sorry, but until now…
いいから来い！
Never mind. Come with me.
Damn it!
ったく こんな ばあちゃん相手に
やりすぎだろ。
She's just a grandma!
That's overkill!
お前は！
You're—!
Oh no, it's that kid…
あら やだ 例の…。
あいつ帰ってきやがったのか。
He's come back, huh?
戻って早々
ルール無用ってわけか。
Breaking the rules
the minute you return?
相変わらず進歩がない。
Seems like you haven't
grown up at all, have you?
Well, you sure have changed.
お前はずいぶん
変わったみてえだけどな。
チョウジ そのおばあちゃんを。
了解。
Choji, take granny.
Right.
– Hey!
– Sorry…
おい！
悪いが➡
but I can't let you pass.
ここは通さねえ。
どうします？ 副隊長。
What do we do, Lieutenant?
任務を妨害されて
引く道理がどこにある。
We're not going to back down
from any obstructions
of our duties.
Still talking about
that kinda stuff?
まだそんなことを。
《この日を待っていた》
I've been waiting for this day…
なんだ？ この感じは。
What is this feeling?
(ダンゾウ)双方控えよ
天下の往来を何と心得る。
Stop it, both of you!
Are you aware that
this is a public road?
あんたは。
You're—!
ダチどうしが拳で話すだけだ。
We're just two friends
having a friendly fight,
関係ねえおっちゃんは
下がっててくれ。
It's none of your business
so back off, old man!
って このバカ！
って 何だよ 何だよ サクラちゃん。
You idiot!
Huh?! What, Sakura?!
Hey!
あんたね…
とにかく ひくわよ。
Let's just get out of here!
Are they going to run away?!
あいつら 逃げる気か！
かまうな 放っておけ。
Forget it. Leave them alone.
だけど…。
命令だ。
But—!
That's an order.
お前らは
そのまま巡回を続けておけ。
Just continue your rounds.
(ダンゾウ)うずまきナルト➡
Naruto Uzumaki…
この３年で
ずいぶん力をつけたようだ。
He's gained a lot of strength
in three years.
師である自来也に
よく導かれたとみえる。
His master Jiraiya has
taught him well.
何が言いたい？
What is it that you want to say?
純粋な疑問よ。
I'm just posing a simple question.
お前はその程度の器ではないはず。
You should be much more
than how you are right now.
いつまで
留まっているつもりなのかとな。
How long will you remain
confined to where you're at?
That's all.
お前 ダンゾウ様相手に
おっちゃん呼ばわりはねえだろ。
You don't just go around
calling someone
like Lord Danzo "old man."
知らねえってばよ 誰だそれ。
I didn't know!
Who the hell was that?
木ノ葉の上層部の１人！
He's one of the Leaf's top officials!
っていうか 四代目や先代様と
敵対してる人じゃない。
In fact, he's the one
who's always at odds
with Lord Fourth
and Lord Third.
油断ならないから
絶対 関わっちゃいけないって➡
Even Lady Tsunade
strictly warned me
綱手様からも
きつく言われてるんだから。
to never get involved with him.
ナルトって ホントに うといよね。
You're so dense, Naruto.
あの さっきはありがとうね。
Thank you for earlier.
ハハハ いや～。
Oh no…
別にたいしたことじゃねえよ。
It's no big deal.
当たり前のことをした…。
じゃあ そういうことだから。
It was the right thing to do…
Well, I must get going.
昔から副隊長様とは
仲が悪かったっていうじゃないか。
I hear he's always been on bad terms
with the Lieutenant.
これ以上 もめごと
起こさねえでくれるといいが。
I just hope he doesn't make
this any worse than it already is.
ちょっと！
いいって。
– Hey!
– It's okay.
気にしたら キリがねえ。
There's no end
to it if you get involved.
More importantly,
getting back to Sasuke…
それより 今はサスケだ。
エロ仙人が言ってたんだ。
Pervy Sage told me…
友達が道を踏み外したら
引き戻してやれって。
If a friend wanders off the path,
you have to pull them back onto it.
だからよ
次こそ サスケを止めねえとな。
So next time,
we have to stop Sasuke.
うん。
Yeah!
なぁ 放っておいていいのか？
副隊長。
Are you sure about
leaving them alone, Lieutenant?
I know he's gonna give
you more trouble!
あいつ 次もサスケさんに盾つく気で。
うるさい。
副隊長！
Shut up!
Lieutenant!
俺は用事がある。
I have work to do.
お前らも
うちは警務部隊の一員なら➡
If you're a member of
the Leaf Police Force,
俺に頼らず判断して動け。
use your own judgment instead
of always depending on me.
((うずまきナルト… この３年で
ずいぶん力をつけたようだ))
Naruto Uzumaki…
He's gained a lot of strength
in three years.
《どんな修業をしたか知らないが
昔とは比べ物にならない。
I don't know how he trained…
But he's nothing like how
he was in the past.
今の俺の力では足りない。
どうしたら…》
I'm not strong enough.
How do I—?!
(シロ)ワン ワン ワン ワン。 クゥ～ン。
That child Sasuke…
あのサスケという小僧
なかなか よい目をしておった。
…possesses fine eyes.
そういや 昨日 うちは警務部隊と
火影の息子が やりあったって。
Oh yeah, the Police Force
had a run-in
with the Hokage's son yesterday.
What?!
えっ やつなら さっき見かけたぞ。
普通に歩いてたぜ。
I just saw them.
They were walking around
like nothing happened.
警務部隊ども
庶民には威張っても➡
So the Police Force acts
all big with us commoners,
but their hands are tied when it comes
to the son of a powerful official, huh?
権力者の息子には手が出せないか。
しょせん 火影の犬だな。
They're just the Hokage's lapdogs,
after all.
Everyone's started gossiping.
もう噂が広まってるぜ。
Letting him go was a big mistake!
(タイコ)やはり
あいつを逃がしたのは失敗だな。
We've been clamping down
on everyone until now.
今まで
厳しく取り締まってきたんだ。
So when we make an exception
and go easy on someone…
例外を認めれば
我らのメンツにかかわる。
they drag us through the mud.
But the Lieutenant said
to leave him alone!
だが 副隊長は放っておけって。
He also entrusted us
to handle things on our own!
そのサスケさんに
一任されているのも俺たちだ。
Thinking about the sake
of our clan,
一族のためにも
正しい判断を下さないとな。
we have to make the right decisions.
(クシナ)今日は
腕によりをかけちゃうんだから。
I'm gonna go all out and
whip up something special today!
What—?!
あんたたち いきなり何なの!?
What's going on?!
You can't just barge
into someone's house…
人の家に しかも土足で！
especially with your dirty shoes on!
Bring us Naruto Uzumaki!
うずまきナルトを出せ。
先日の任務妨害の件で話がある。
We want to question him about
interfering with our duties the other day.
そんなの聞いてない。 任務妨害？
I know nothing about it.
Interfering with your duty?
そもそも うちの息子が
そんなことするはずないってばね。
My son would never
do such a thing!
だいたい 誰の許可で
こんなことしてるわけ!?
Besides, on whose authority
are you acting?
I'm going to tell Minato and you're going
to get an earful, y'know!
ミナトに言って
しかってもらうってばね。
If you try to protect him,
we'll take you with us too!
かばうなら お前も連行するぞ！
What's the big idea…
いきなり 押しかけて➡
barging in like this?
なんのつもりだ。
Excuse me.
失礼します。
なんだ？
What is it?
The captain wants to see you.
隊長が お呼びです。
Please come with me now, Lieutenant.
副隊長 今すぐご同行ください。
I had some misgivings,
危惧は しておったが
まさか警務部隊の者が➡
but I never expected
the members of the Police Force
手続きも踏まず いきなり
火影の家に踏み込むとは。
would raid the Hokage's residence
without the proper authorization.
たいへん
申し訳ありませんでした。
My sincerest apologies.
Well, at least no one was hurt.
とにかく
ケガ人が出なかったのは幸いだよ。
それで フガクさんは？
(イタチ)捨て置けないと。
So, what does Fugaku
think about all of this?
He knows that he has
to take action now.
しかるべき処分を
下すことになるでしょう。
I'm sure he'll take appropriate
measures of discipline.
これで少しは落ち着くとよいが。
I just hope they ease up a little now.
お前たち。
You guys!
すみません 副隊長。
We're sorry, Lieutenant!
We only did this for
the sake of the Uchiha.
俺たちはただ うちはのために。
もういい。 こいつらは
牢にでも閉じ込めておけ。
Enough.
Lock them up.
ハッ。
Sir!
You said you'd take
a different path.
違う道を行くとお前は言ったな。
そして 力を身につけた。
And you did become stronger.
あれだけの口を叩いたのだ➡
But after all that boasting,
幾分かは ものになったと
思いたかったが…。
I had hoped there was
some substance to it.
But I guess it was for nothing.
やはり 無駄だったようだな。
What you ended up doing
was empowering fools
結局 お前のしたことは
愚か者をつけあがらせ➡
to indulge in idiotic behavior.
バカげた行動へ走らせただけ。
成し得たことなど ひとつもない。
Nothing good came out of this.
兄のイタチには 到底及ばぬ。
You will never measure up
to your brother Itachi!
I don't need someone
like you in my unit.
俺の隊に
お前のような者はいらん。
ただいまをもって
お前の副隊長職を剥奪。
You are hereby relieved
of your duties as lieutenant.
警務部隊から追放する。
I am dismissing you
from the Leaf Police Force.
警務部隊が そんなことを…。
The Leaf Police Force did that?
サスケ君の処分は
どうなっちゃうのかな。
So what's going to happen
to Sasuke?
わからねえ。 でも➡
I don't know.
But I wouldn't be surprised
if he's fired from the force.
もし この件で警務部隊を
クビになるってんなら しかたねえ。
We'll just slap him on the back
一発 ガツンとやって➡
and welcome him back
into our team again.
俺らの班に
迎え入れてやるってばよ。
うん。
Okay!
《なんだ… この３年間。
What the hell…
…was I doing for
the last three years?
俺は 何をしてきた。
やつと 何が違うんだ！》
Why is he so different from me?!
It's power… I need power.
《力だ… 力が欲しい！》
来たか。
You've come.
あんたが呼んだんだろ
何か 目論見があって。
You called me,
so you must have
something up your sleeve.
誘えば 俺が乗ると見越して
声をかけてきた。
I just came to see
what you're offering.
フン… 見越して
なお わざわざやってきたと？
You came just to see?
I want to take advantage of you too.
俺もまた あんたを利用したい。
いい話し合いになると思ってな。
I figured we'd have
a nice little chat.
それで お前の望みは？
And? What do you want?
力が欲しい。
I want power…
あいつを倒すほどの。
Enough to beat him.
I predicted as much.
おおよその予測はしていたがな。
だが よいのか？
But…are you sure?
Not only is Naruto Uzumaki
the Hokage's son…
うずまきナルトは
火影の息子であると同時に➡
この里にとっては
重要な 九尾の人柱力でもある。
he's also the Jinchuriki
of the Nine Tails,
which is essential to this village.
If you realize your goal,
it's possible
目的を果たせば
うちは一族の立場が➡
that the Uchiha's standing
in the village will worsen.
悪くなることも考えられるが。
関係ない。
I don't care.
あいつをやることが 俺のすべて。
Beating him means
everything to me…
うちはも 木ノ葉もどうでもいい。
I don't care about
the Uchiha or the Hidden Leaf.
フッ。
何がおかしい？
What's so funny?
I remember a shinobi who
deserted the village long ago
昔 似たようなことを言って➡
里を抜けた忍を思い出してな。
saying something
along those lines…
その者は すべてを裏切り
数多くの罪と引き換えに➡
He betrayed everyone,
committed numerous crimes
and in exchange…
恐るべき力を手に入れた。
obtained frightening power.
その者の名は 大蛇丸。
His name is Orochimaru…
ナルトの師である 自来也と同じ➡
One of the Legendary Sannin,
like Jiraiya, Naruto's mentor.
伝説の三忍だ。
伝説の三忍…。
The Legendary Sannin.
He has knowledge of
the myriad jutsu
やつは 禁術を含む
この世のあらゆる術に精通する。
that exist in this world
including forbidden ones.
お前が学びを得る相手としては
申し分なかろう。
I can't think of a better person
to learn from than him.
ただし あやつは
闇の中で生きてきた男。
However…he is a man
who has lived within the darkness.
それなりの代償は 覚悟しておけ。
Remember that's the price you'll pay.
望むところだ。
I'm looking forward to it.
よかろう。
Fine then.
Before sunrise,
go to the tower at the border.
では 日が昇る前に
国境の塔へ行け。
あとは 段取りをつけておく。
I'll take care of the rest.
まだ話は終わっていない！
We're not done yet.
あんたの目的を聞くまではな。
I want to know what
you get out of this.
信じるかは勝手だが…
わしも あの化け物➡
It's your choice to believe me
or to not…
But I am one among many
who do not look too kindly
九尾を快く思わぬ
人間の一人でな。
on that monster, the Nine Tails.
いつ暴走し
大暴れするかもしれぬ化け物を➡
It's a monster that could
rampage at any moment,
I question if it's wise to leave
such a power unbridled…
野放しにしておくのもどうかと。
I feel we need the power
to fight against it.
こちらにも抗う力は
必要だということだ。
フン…。
行け。
Go.
これで 契約は果たした。
あとは お前次第。
We have a contract now.
The rest is up to you.
シロ。
元気でな。
ク～ン… ワン！
フフフフ！
やっぱり 夜のおやつは➡
コッテリ系に決まりだよね。
サスケ？ こんな時間に
どこ行くんだろ？
ヘイ 唐揚げ５人前 おまけつき！
おっ やったぁ！
(コテツ)よっしゃ 任務終わり！
(イズモ)閉門 閉門っと。
(イズモ)この時間からの外出届は
出ていなかったはずだが。
(コテツ)おい 閉門時間だぞ。
(イズモ)待て…。
＜ あれから何年経ったかしら。
過ぎてみれば懐かしい。
泣くも笑うも 夢ひとつ＞